Guide to the Irving S. Olds Papers 1818-1963 MS 325
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Photographs & Ephemera, 1907-1962; 1.38 Linear feet
  - Photos - Cooper Union, 1956-1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
    Contains photos from events at Cooper Union, a university in which Olds was heavily involved, such as groundbreaking ceremonies, official dinners, commencements, and installations of new administrators
  - Photos - Waldorf Astoria, 1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
    Contains photos from the Dinner of the National Fund for Medical Education at the Waldorf Astoria
  - Photos - 55th Reunion of Olds's Graduation from Yale, 1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Photo - Wagner, Robert F., c. 1950s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
    Photograph of Olds with Mayor Wagner, featuring an autograph by Wagner
  - Photos - Miscellaneous, 1952-1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
    Includes but is not limited to photos of Olds taken at universities such as Cooper Union, Syracuse, Drexel, and Yale, a photo from the dinner celebrating the 150th anniversary of the formation of N-YHS, photos of Olds participating in a New York Public Library fundraiser, photos of people possibly connected to the Blooming Grove Park Association, and photos of the SS Irving S Olds. Also includes one photograph taken in 1960 in Moscow of the World's Fair 1964-65 Delegation, which includes Olds, USSR Foreign Minister Gromyko, and the other members of the committee.
  - Photos - Reunions, 1958-1961 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
    Contains 1960 reunion photos from Harvard Law School, Class of 1910, a 1957 photo of Yale Class of 1907, and a photo from each of the annual dinners of the U.S. Steel corporation from 1958-1961
  - Photo - White and Case Group, c. 1950s (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photos - White and Case Portraits, 1929-1942 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
    Includes individual photos of Franklin Remington, Charles Fay, and Justin White, all inscribed by the subjects. Also includes a photo of Perley Noyes along with his memorial booklet
  - Photo - Opening Night at Lincoln Center, 1962 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
  - Dinner Menu from White and Case Anniversary Celebration, 1926 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
  - Awards (2 folders), 1941-1963 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 10-11)
    Contains a booklet commemorating Olds, presented to him upon his retirement from U.S. Steel, and certificates from American Judicature Society, Chamber of Commerce, Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York Public Library Citizens Advisory Committee, Board of Governors of the American Red Cross, American Bar Association, Academy of Political Science in the City of New York, United States Department of the Navy, Trans World Airlines Ambassadors Club, and National Wildlife Federation
  - Awards, 1907-1948 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
    Contains certificates from the Pinnacle Club, Yale University, Sons of the Revolution, 1964-65 New York World's Fair, Society of the New York Hospital, and New-York Historical Society
  - Erie (Pennsylvania) High School diploma, 1903 (Folder Oversize-Large)
  - Passports, 1920 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 13)
  - Yale Ephemera, 1859-1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 14)
  - Elihu Yale Poster, 1962 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Ephemera, 1941-1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 15)
  - News Clippings, 1940-1961 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Steel Clippings, 1947-1952 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 17)
- Series VI. Subject Files, 1818-1963; 6.3 Linear feet
  The final series contains subject files which pertain to various topics such as Olds's family history or personal and real property.
  The first half or so of the series are alphabetized subject files, while the remaining subject files are grouped by category. They primarily fall into the categories of family history and personal financial records. There are four folders of oversized material in box 12, in addtion to one large oversize folder.
  - Biographies, 1955-1962 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 18)
    Contains biographical sketches about Olds
  - Booklet of Speeches, 1823-1860 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 19)
    Contains reproductions of published speeches given by Usher Parsons, William Sprague, and Jesse Duncan Elliott
  - Manuscripts of Remarks, 1952-1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 20)
    Contains manuscripts of Olds's remarks: "The Steel Industry Progresses" from 1955, "The Steel Strike of 1952", "Early American Naval Prints" from 1960
  - Exhibits, 1957-1959 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 21)
    Contains materials about Naval Print Exhibits that Olds had planned
  - Ex-Monarch's Club, 1929-1931 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 22)
    Contains certificates of membership, and materials regarding the annual dinners in 1929, 1930, and 1931. There is some connection between this club and the Foundation Company, which was a client of Olds's at White & Case.
  - Gettysburg Address, 1944-1963 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 23)
    Contains a reproduction of the Gettysburg Address, with edits written over it. There is a note that this version is "As Mr. Fay would have written." This is presumably a reference to Olds's colleague at White & Case, Charles Faye. There is also a page from the January 30, 1962 issue of the New York Times about President Kennedy's attempts to allegedly micromanage remarks that come out of the Government. The article makes reference to a Bob Newhart comedy sketch discussing how "Madison Ave" would have altered the Gettysburg Address.
  - Hartfeld, Joseph, 1955 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 24)
    Contains materials relating to the 50th anniversary dinner of Joseph Hartfield and Leonard Hull Smith
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1886-1935 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 25)
    Contains full issues of the New York Times Magazine Section from March 7, 1926, the New York Herald Tribune Magazine from February 7, 1932, Harper's Weekly from June 5, 1886, and the Yale Law Journal from March 1931. These publications all feature articles about Justice Holmes. There is also a large stack of news clippings from various papers about Holmes.
  - Nassau Community College, 1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 26)
    Contains the NCC First Annual Report, from the 1959-1960 academic year
  - Obituaries, Olds, 1922-1963 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 27)
    Contains obituaries for Irving Olds and his father, Clark Olds
  - Patriotic Education, Inc. (Offsite-box 9, Folder 28)
    Contains a booklet explaining the purpose of the organization
  - Theodore Roosevelt Award, 1960 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 29)
    Contains materials, remarks, and photographs regarding Olds having been given the Roosevelt Award
  - Historic Deeds, 1890-1922 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
    Contains Olds family property records from Erie County, Pennsylvania
  - Land Records, 1818-1906 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
    Contains Pennsylvania land patents from 1832 and 1906 and conveyances from 1818 and 1827
  - Genealogy, Keator Family, 1943-1961 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
    Contains documents pertaining to and narratives describing the history of Irving Olds's mother's family
  - Family Letters, 1862-1906 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
  - Foster (Cornell) Family History, 1906-1922 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
    Contains materials related to the genealogy of Evelyn Foster Olds's family
  - Clark Olds, 1921-1946 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
    Contains letters between Irving Olds and his father, Clark Olds, written while Irving was living in France to expand White & Case's business abroad. Also contains a poem written by Clark, and photos of Clark's dog from the 1920s.
  - Securities (2 folders), 1867-1910 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6-7)
    Contains a variety of stock certificates for now defunct corporations
  - Bonds, 1867-1878 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
    Coupon bonds of the Lebanon Springs Railroad Company
  - 216 W 7th St, 1888-1947 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
    Contains records of a parcel the Oldses owned in Erie, Pennsylvania
  - Peter M Cauley Trust, 1915-1930 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    Financial records of a reverend from Erie, Pennsylvania, who may have been a friend or associate of the Olds family
  - Wayne St, 1922-1953 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
  - 24 E 42nd St, 1961-1962 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
    Contains records about a property owned by N-YHS for much of the mid 20th century
  - Woodbury Subdivision (1 of 2), 1928-1955 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 12)
    Contains records about property Olds owned in Nassau County, New York.
  - Woodbury Subdivision (2 of 2), Oversize, 1930-1940 (Folder Oversize-Large)
    Contains oversize maps and blueprints about property Olds owned in Nassau County, New York. There are references to his property being involved in the construction of the Northern State Parkway.
  - Misc. Property Records, 1918-1947 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 13)
    Contains records of two property transactions from Erie, Pennsylvania, one involving Irving, and one involving his father, Clark
  - Real Estate Taxes (2 folders), 1940-1955 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Medical Receipts, 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 16)
  - Life Insurance Receipts, 1949-1963 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 17)
  - Paper about Alabama Claims, 1910 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 18)
    A handwritten paper by Olds about Reconstruction-era Alabama